<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>career on smcleod.net</title><link>https://smcleod.net/tags/career/</link><description>Recent content in career on smcleod.net</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><copyright>Sam McLeod</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 08:10:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://smcleod.net/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Camels Dressed As Unicorns</title><link>https://smcleod.net/2019/08/camels-dressed-as-unicorns/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 08:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smcleod.net/2019/08/camels-dressed-as-unicorns/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="stop-trying-to-hire-with-titles-like-devops-engineer-or-cloud-engineer">Stop trying to hire with titles like ‘DevOps Engineer&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Cloud Engineer&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;DevOps is &amp;hellip; not a job title&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s more of a cultural practice, like innovation, and it makes just as little sense hiring &amp;ldquo;innovation engineers&amp;rdquo; and expecting your organisation to be innovative, without also creating the culture to foster innovation.&amp;rdquo; (Joel Shea when responding to this posted on &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/activity-6564991913110368256-WxFP">LinkedIn&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In most cases it&amp;rsquo;s clear the organisation doesn&amp;rsquo;t truly know what they want or need and likely don&amp;rsquo;t understand the nuances of the aspects of engineering.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem is - they&amp;rsquo;re going to end up with a ‘Camel Dressed As A Unicorn&amp;rsquo; rather than someone with deep or natural engineering understanding in the areas they most need to help see, discuss, solve problems and deliver effective and lasting solutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen recently companies hiring with &amp;lsquo;DevOps Engineer&amp;rsquo; titles - the organisation (thinks they) want / need a Developer with a little bit of Operations experience - but not a true understanding of Operations or platform engineering.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m almost certain they&amp;rsquo;re trying to appeal to the hype (in a genuine effort to find someone highly skilled) but as they&amp;rsquo;re missing the point of where people&amp;rsquo;s skills lay and what those skills mean - they&amp;rsquo;re confusing engineers, recruiters and likely themselves further.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="devops-is-_deeply_-important">DevOps is &lt;em>deeply&lt;/em> important&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Likely the most important thing to succeed at product and systems delivery - but it&amp;rsquo;s not a job title.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you need Developers to work in a DevOps culture and environment - say so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you need Operations or Platform Engineers to work in a DevOps culture and environment - say so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Staying either of those does not mutually exclude ones abilities to know &amp;lsquo;a bit of the other side&amp;rsquo;, e.g. a Developer that has worked closely with a CI/CD system&amp;rsquo;s backend or Kubernetes Operations, or an Operations Engineer that has worked closely with Developers and Testers and can work with APIs: or whip up some integration scripts when needed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Looking For New Opportunities</title><link>https://smcleod.net/2019/08/looking-for-new-opportunities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smcleod.net/2019/08/looking-for-new-opportunities/</guid><description>&lt;p>As stated in &lt;a href="https://smcleod.net/tech/2019/06/29/leaving-infoxchange.html">my announcement post&lt;/a> - after 7~ years, I resigned from Infoxchange several months ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I planned on taking a holiday, relaxing, decompressing, dipping my toes in some off-the-shelf tech I haven&amp;rsquo;t spent a lot of time with and performing some personal growth through reading a number of books that have been sitting on my &amp;rsquo;to read&amp;rsquo; shelf.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is exactly what I&amp;rsquo;ve done.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Leaving Infoxchange</title><link>https://smcleod.net/2019/06/leaving-infoxchange/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smcleod.net/2019/06/leaving-infoxchange/</guid><description>&lt;p>After 7~ years, I have resigned from Infoxchange.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>In 2012 I was hired to work with &lt;a href="https://www.infoxchange.org">Infoxchange&lt;/a> to &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;shake things up&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> (in the Systems Operations team) and stabilise the hosting environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As Team Lead of Systems Operations I was tasked with melding the team and then for us to work to provide a stable, robust, modern and scalable platform
for Infoxchange developed application hosting and product delivery and in a short time, with a small budget - we did just that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This 7~ year journey was exciting, rewarding and of course at times very stressful.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AskIzzy</title><link>https://smcleod.net/2016/01/askizzy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smcleod.net/2016/01/askizzy/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="today-we-launched-a-mobile-website-for-homeless-people">Today we launched a mobile website for homeless people&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip; and it was launched by &lt;a href="http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/victoria/askizzy-app-connects-the-homeless-to-food-shelter-and-health-services/news-story/bfae67275552be421af4dd54bfd575a6?nk=ebd042d1d2789514c4e8553cb5633711-1454053888">Australia&amp;rsquo;s Prime Minister&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="today-we-served-up-over-87000-requests-to-the-site-and-its-only-in-its-first-stage-of-inception">Today we served up over 87,000 requests to the site and it&amp;rsquo;s only in it&amp;rsquo;s first stage of inception&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>As many of you know, I work with &lt;a href="https://infoxchange.org">Infoxchange&lt;/a> as the operations lead.
When I first heard the idea of a website or app for people that have found or are worried about finding themselves homeless in Australia I really didn&amp;rsquo;t think it made sense - until I saw the stats showing how many homeless people in Australia have regular access to a smart phone and data either via a cellular provider or free WiFi.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We did a lot of research, working with homeless and at-risk people throughout Australia, it&amp;rsquo;s really been quite an eye opener especially for my team who are largely technically focused.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AskIzzy is the result of Infoxchange winning the Google Impact Challenge in 2015. For me the most interesting things about the site other than it&amp;rsquo;s value to those in need is that it didn&amp;rsquo;t cost tax payers a cent to develop or host and it has no model for making profit of any kind, this resulted in the site being designed truly for the end consumer - the person in need.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Search - A Journey of Delivery on a Budget</title><link>https://smcleod.net/2015/02/search-a-journey-of-delivery-on-a-budget/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smcleod.net/2015/02/search-a-journey-of-delivery-on-a-budget/</guid><description>Presented a Melbourne Search - July 2014 - &amp;lsquo;Search - A Journey of Delivery on a Budget&amp;rsquo;.
![]({{ site.url }}/img/es/es.png)
![View Slides]({{ site.url }}/img/misc/search.jpg)
Video here</description></item><item><title>Talk - 24 Months</title><link>https://smcleod.net/2015/02/talk-24-months/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smcleod.net/2015/02/talk-24-months/</guid><description>The way we work at Infoxchange has changed greatly.
A retrospective journey into transforming Infoxchange&amp;rsquo;s technology and culture over the past 24 months - presented a Melbourne DevOps - December 2014
![Click to Download Slides]({{ site.url }}/img/misc/24months.jpg)</description></item></channel></rss>