<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>software on smcleod.net</title><link>https://smcleod.net/categories/software/</link><description>Recent content in software on smcleod.net</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><copyright>Sam McLeod</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://smcleod.net/categories/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Firefox Addons for 2022</title><link>https://smcleod.net/2022/05/firefox-addons-for-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smcleod.net/2022/05/firefox-addons-for-2022/</guid><description>Firefox Addons - 2022 Edition My list of must-have Firefox addons - 2022 edition
Updated: 2022-10-09
Privacy and Security Firstly - you should have Firefox&amp;rsquo;s Enhanced Tracking Protection enabled.
Don&amp;rsquo;t Track Me Google LocalCDN UTM Tracking Token Stripper Note: You can accomplish some of what this does by setting up the removeparam uBlock origin rules I&amp;rsquo;ve listed below. Multi-Account Containers Useful for setting sites such as Amazon, eBay, Twitter, LinkedIn, Banking etc&amp;hellip; each to always open in their own isolated container.</description></item><item><title>Goodbye Evernote, Hello Bear</title><link>https://smcleod.net/2021/07/goodbye-evernote-hello-bear/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smcleod.net/2021/07/goodbye-evernote-hello-bear/</guid><description>&lt;p>Until recently I used Evernote for my notes, web clippings and document drafts, I was a subscriber going on 14 years and had over 3000 notes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However in recent years Evernote has gone downhill to the point it could be considered hostile to it&amp;rsquo;s users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The native macOS app was replaced with an Electron Javascript webframe and like almost all Electron apps I&amp;rsquo;ve tried it was plagued by poor performance, memory leaks and aggressive idle CPU utilisation and above all else it now lacks the low latency feeling the native application had.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the release of the updated client, Evernote has removed offline note functionality - tough luck if you&amp;rsquo;re travelling or don&amp;rsquo;t have reliable internet access.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This year I finally decided I had enough and have spent several months testing out alternatives including Bear, Notion, Ulysses, Simplenote, IA Writer and several others.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>